Guide to the Board of Trustees records, 1821-2003 RG0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Board of Trustees records
1821-2010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Board of Trustees
RG0001
23.75 Linear Feet
Collection include meeting minutes (original and microfilm), correspondence, charters and by-laws, committee files, and congressional documents relating to the University.
Collection note
Partial index to the minutes of the Board are kept with second copy of microfilm. Please see staff for assistance.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Board of Trustees.
Biographical Note
The management, direction, and government of George Washington University is vested in a Board of Trustees. Pursuant to the by-laws of the University, the Board consists of the President as an ex officio member, three alumni or alumnae members elected to the Board at each annual meeting for terms of three years; with one alumni Trustee being a "recent graduate" who serves for one term of three years and two Alumni Trustees serving for a maximum of two terms of three years; and the balance of not less than thirty nor more than forty-five persons, each elected to the Board for three year terms. Trustees elected after January 1, 1992 may not serve more than three consecutive terms without stepping down for a minimum of one year, after which they are eligible for reelection. Persons are qualified to serve as Trustees regardless of race, color, creed, sex, national origin, or place of residence. With the exception of the President, no person who is an officer, professor, lecturer, teacher, tutor, student or employee of the University, or is 75 years of age or older, is eligible to serve as a Trustee. The Executive Committee is responsible for taking all actions and exercising all powers of the Board, except that it may not elect Trustees, amend the by-laws or approve the merger of any other corporation with the University. The Executive Committee consists of the Chairman of the Board, as chairman, the President, and at least eight Trustees appointed by the chairman for a one year term.
The University operates under a charter granted by an Act of Congress on February 9, 1821 to the Columbian College in the District of Columbia. In 1873, the name was changed to Columbian University and in 1904 to The George Washington University.
From 1872 to 1900 the Board of Trustees was known as the Board of Overseers. The Board approves curriculum, tuition, faculty hires, etc. The Board appoints various committees which are empowered to act between meetings of the full Board. These include the Executive, Academic Affairs, Financial Affairs, Audit, Buildings and Grounds, Compensation, Medical Center, Development, Student and Alumni Affairs, Trusteeship, External Affairs, Investments, and University Trusteeship Committees.
Former prominent members represented in this collection include: Luther Rice, John Quincy Adams, Peter Force, Joseph Henry, William Corcoran, Amos Kendall, Edward Gallaudet, Alexander Graham Bell, Gilbert Grosvenor, Ulysses S. Grant III, and J. Edgar Hoover.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include meeting minutes (original and microfilm), correspondence, charters and by-laws, committee files, and congressional documents relating to the University. These materials range in date from 1821 to 2003 and includes early correspondence going back to the 1820's, biographical information on Trustees, and the physical development of the University and evolution of schools and departments. Elmer Kayser's book on the history of the University, "Bricks Without Straw" was based on information found in the Board of Trustees records. The material was transferred to the University Archives by the Board of Trustees and the University Historian.
Former prominent members represented in this collection include: Luther Rice, John Quincy Adams, Peter Force, Joseph Henry, William Corcoran, Amos Kendall, Edward Gallaudet, Alexander Graham Bell, Gilbert Grosvenor, Ulysses S. Grant III, and J. Edgar Hoover.
Collection Organization
Organized into eight series: Papers, Microfilm, George Washington University's annual fund, George Washington University's charter, Committees, Congressional documents, Faculty, and Records.
Restrictions on Use
Series 1, 2, and 5 are closed to research for 50 years from date of record creation.
Finance; Students; By-laws; Washington (D.C.); Committees; Biography; Board of Trustees; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; Columbian College in the District of Columbia; Columbian University; Henry, Joseph; Corcoran, W. W. (William Wilson); Adams, John Quincy; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar); Luther Rice; George Washington University; Force, Peter; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey
- Papers, 1821-2010; RG0001 Series 1; 12.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  The series is a collection of the Board of Trustees' minutes, correspondence, biographical data, and by-laws. They range in date from 1821 to 1999. NOTE: There is no Box 1 and 2, they are found in Series 2.
  - University Charter of 9 Feb. 1821, certified copy, 03/03/1873 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1 draft of the first minutes, 03/05/1821 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1822 -1824 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1825 -1826 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1828 -1830 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1833 -1838 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1854 -1855 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1857 -1861 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, with John R. Poradley, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees general correspondence, 1895 -1896 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees general correspondence, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees general correspondence, report to treasurer, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees proxies for 1829 elections, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees election, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees election, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustees proxy for elections, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Board of Trustees faculty recommendations of candidates for degrees, 1835 -1855 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Transfer of Title to College Hill from O.B. Brown and Baptist general convention to Columbus College, 06/29/1846 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - President's house: building contract, correspondence, 1868 -1869 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Board of Trustees: special committee, 1908 -1910 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - National university Board of Trustee Minutes (folder) from: 9 Nov. 1954; 19 May 1955; 5 Oct. 1955; 9 Feb. 1956; 10 May 1956; 21 Feb. 1957; 9 May 1957; 10 Oct. 1957; 13 March 1958; 8 May 1958; 23 Jan. 1959, 1954 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - National University: Incorporation, Board of Trustees correspondences, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - By-laws of the Board, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Endowment Fund, 1875 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fund-raising, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Individual Trustee: Grant, Ulysses, Sr., undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Individual Trustee: Grant, Ulysses, III, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Individual Trustee: Kendall, Amos, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Individual Trustee: Morris, Edward Karrick, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Individual Trustee: Phillips, Charles E., undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Individual Trustee: Reynolds, Enoch, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Individual Trustee: Snow, Alpheus, H., undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Individual Trustee: Strauss, Lewis L., undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Individual Trustee: Woodhull, Maxwell Van Zandt, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Individual Trustees' Biographical Data (alphabetical): A-G, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Individual Trustees' Biographical Data (alphabetical): H-Z, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Individual Trustees' Biographical Data (not arranged), undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Board of Trustee brochures, 1967-1993; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 1-6)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Board records are closed for 50 years.
  - Condensed biographical sketches, 1965-1974; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Trustee lists, 1958-1970; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 8-14)
  - Board correspondence, 1928-1974; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 15-40)
  - Release of chairman and secretary, 6/1/1965; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 41)
  - Study for the Board of Trustees at GWU, 6/21/1955; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 42)
  - Property holdings, 1/6/1937; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 43)
  - Development of graduate study, 4/1/1937; Series 1 (Box 54, Folder 44)
  - Membership Lists, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of Meetings, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Student Membership, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Tuition Increases, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Brown, Obediah (letters by Joseph Cone, Robert Semple, Henry Morfitt), 1827 -1829 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Galusha (letters by Joshua More and Mark Harris), 1827 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Larner, John B. (speeches), 1913 -1924 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reynolds, Enoch (letter by George Wood), 1830 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rogers, Rev. William (letter by Enoch Reynolds), 1823 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Temple, John T. (letter from the Board), 1832 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Wood, George (letters by Robert Semple), 1830 -1831 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Woodhull, Maxwell van Zandt, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified authors, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.1, 03/05/1821 --03/18/1835 (Volume 1)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.2, 05/20/1835 --08/10/1859 (Volume 2)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.3, 10/12/1859 --06/07/1882 (Volume 3)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.4, 06/14/1882 --06/13/1894 (Volume 4)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.5, 06/18/1894 --06/04/1902 (Volume 5)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.6, 06/18/1902 --05/26/1910 (Volume 6)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.7, 06/01/1910 --01/14/1920 (Volume 7)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.8, 01/20/1920 --03/12/1931 (Volume 8)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.9, 06/04/1931 --06/04/1940 (Volume 9)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.10, 10/10/1940 --03/10/1949 (Volume 10)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.11, 05/19/1949 --10/11/1956 (Volume 11)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.12, 12/13/1956 --03/15/1962 (Volume 12)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.13, 05/10/1962 --10/13/1965 (Volume 13)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.14, 01/20/1966 --03/17/1966 (Volume 14)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.15, 06/04/1966 --10/16/1969 (Volume 15)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.16, 01/15/1970 --05/18/1972 (Volume 16)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.17, 10/19/1972 --01/16/1975 (Volume 17)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.18, 03/20/1975 --05/19/1977 (Volume 18)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.19, 10/20/1977 --10/18/1979 (Volume 19)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.20, 01/17/1980 --10/21/1982 (Volume 20)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.21, 01/20/1983 --03/21/1985 (Volume 21)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.22, 05/16/1985 --05/15/1986 (Volume 22)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.23, 10/16/1986 --05/19/1988 (Volume 23)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.24, 10/20/1988 -- 3/15/1990 (Volume 24)
    Board records restricted for 50 years.
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.25, 5/17/1990 -- 10/17/1991 (Volume 25)
    Board records closed for 50 years.
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.26, 1/16/1992 -- 5/7/1993 (Volume 26)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.27, 10/28/1993 -- 2/8/1996 (Volume 27)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.28, 5/17/1996 -- 10/31/1997 (Volume 28)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.29, 2/13/1998 -- 10/22/1999 (Volume 29)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.30, 2/11/2000 - 10/29/2001 (Volume 30)
    Board records are restricted for 50 years.
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.31, 2/8/2002 - 10/17/2003 (Volume 31)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.32, 2/6/2004 -- 6/17/2005 (Volume 32)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.33, 10/21/2005 -- 12/11/2006 (Volume 33)
  - Board of Trustee minutes, v.34, 2/9/2007 -- 2/8/2008 (Volume 34)
  - Additional 1904 A (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Records: Building and Grounds Committee (bound, only 10 pages filled), 11/12/1924 --03/03/1925 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Index to vol.5-6, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1892 -1895 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Superintending Committee, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1859 -1860 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of executive committee, Board of Trustees (bound), 1874 -1877 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee notes (bound), 1877 -1892 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee minutes (bound), 1892 -1897 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Matters, minutes, meetings, etc.; 'Ordinances for School of Medicine,' (bound), 01/16/1924 --10/29/1930 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - National University, Board of Trustee Minutes, Audit Reports (bound volume), Charter and By-Laws, 05/16/1936 --02/28/1954 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 4/25/1919 -- 2/19/1959; Series 1 (Box 55)
    Scope and Contents
    The materials in this box are individual folders of minutes. These are most likely identical to the Board minutes in volumes. The actual dates of minutes are 4/15/1919, 5/18/1922, 5/31/1923 followed by 2/10/1949 until 2/19/1959.
  - Minutes, 6/2/1932 -- 12/9/1948; Series 1 (Box 50)
    The materials in this box are individual folders of minutes. These are most likely identical to the Board minutes in volumes.
  - Minutes, 12/13/1945 -- 10/27/1995; Series 1 (Box 59)
    The materials in this box are individual folders of minutes. These are most likely identical to the Board minutes in volumes. The actual dates of minutes are 12/13/1945, 5/20/1948, 1971-1972, 1986-1995.
  - Minutes, 3/11/1926 -- 5/10/1962; Series 1 (Box 51)
    The materials in this box are individual folders of minutes. These are most likely identical to the Board minutes in volumes. The dates in this box are 3/11/1926-5/13/1932, 10/21/1948, and 5/9/1957-5/10/1962.
  - Minutes, 10/11/1962 -- 5/20/1971; Series 1 (Box 56)
  - Minutes, 1/16/1969 -- 5/18/1978; Series 1 (Box 57)
  - Minutes, 1/18/1973 -- 5/17/1990; Series 1 (Box 58)
  - Minutes, 2/8/1996 -- 2/6/2004; Series 1 (Box 52)
    Materials are restricted for 50 years.
  - Minutes, 5/14/2004 -- 2/12/2010; Series 1 (Box 53)
  - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1988-1990, 10/20/1988 --03/15/1990 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    Board of Trustees minutes ranging from 10/20/1988 to 3/15/1990.
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1990-1991, 05/17/1990 --10/17/1991 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Board of Trustees minutes, 5/17/1990 to 10/17/1991
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1992-1993, 01/16/1992 --05/07/1993 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    Board of Trustees minutes, 01/16/1992 to 05/07/1993.
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1993-1996, 10/28/1993 --02/08/1996 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    Board of Trustee minutes, 10/28/1993-02/08/1996.
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1998-1999, 02/13/1998 --10/22/1999 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Board of Trustees minutes, 02/13/1998 to 10/22/1999
- Microfilm, 1821-1988; RG0001 Series 2; 4 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
  This series is a collection of microfilm covering the minutes of The George Washington University's Board of Trustees. They range in date from 1821 to 1988.
  - Vol. 1-Vol. 3, 03/05/1821 --06/07/1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 4-Vol. 5, 06/14/1882 --06/04/1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 6-Vol. 7, 06/18/1902 --01/14/1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 8-Vol. 9, 01/20/1920 --06/04/1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 10-Vol. 12, 10/10/1940 --03/15/1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 13-Vol. 15, 05/10/1962 --10/16/1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 16-Vol. 17, 01/15/1970 --01/16/1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 18, 03/20/1975 --05/19/1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes Addendum, 10/1977 --10/1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes Addendum, 01/1980 --10/1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes Addendum, 01/1983 --03/1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes Addendum, 05/1985 --05/1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Additional Minutes, Exec. Comm. A 1904 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Additional Minutes, Exec. Comm. B-Bldg. and Ground Committee, 11/12/1924 --03/03/1925 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Additional Minutes, Index Vol. V-VI, 06/11/1877 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Additional Minutes, Exec. Comm., 02/07/1941 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Additional Minutes, Exec. Comm., 02/07/1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Additional Minutes, Trustees'/Dean's Book, part 1, 1839 -1880 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Additional Minutes, Trustees'/Dean's Book, part 2, 1880 -1903 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Print master, 2013 (Box 6)
    General
    Box contains Reels #1-14 and dates of the minutes from 1821-1988. The reels were made in 2013.
  - Print master, 2013 (Box 7)
    Box contains Reel #15-19. The reels were made in 2013.
- George Washington University's annual fund, 1970-1971; RG0001 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  It is a collection from the Board of Trustees of letters, brochures, and other papers. They range in date from 1970 to 1971. They regard The George Washington University's annual fund.
  Formerly ACC#532
- George Washington University's charter, 1821-1988; RG0001 Series 4; 1 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1)
  This series is a collection of a charter, by-laws, an ordinance, a code, and regulations of The George Washington University and its predecessors. They range in date from 1821 to the present.
  - Folder 1, undated (Box 1)
  - Columbian University- Charter and By-Laws, 1821 -1904 (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
  - The Charter and Acts Supplementary Thereto and The By-Laws of The Board of Trustees of The George Washington University Washington, D.C., circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
  - Folder 2, undated (Box 1)
  - University Bulletin Vol. 1, No. 2- The Columbian University Washington, D.C., 12/1902 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
  - The George Washington University Bulletin Vol. IX, No. 4, 12/1910 (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
  - The Board of Trustees of the Columbian University, circa 1902 (Box 1, Folder 2.3)
  - The Charter and Acts Supplementary Thereto and The By-Laws of The Board of Trustees of The George Washington University Washington, D.C., circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2.4)
  - Folder 3, undated (Box 1)
  - The George Washington University Ordinances and Code Governing The Academic Personnel, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
  - Regulations Adopted by The Board of Trustees of the University, Effective in The Departments of Arts and Sciences and Law, 09/01/1926 (Box 1, Folder 3.2)
  - The George Washington University By-Laws and Ordinance, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3.3)
  - Columbian University Ordinance Providing for The Conduct of The Departments of Medicine and Dentistry and The University Hospital, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3.4)
  - The Columbian University- Its Charter, And Other Acts of Legislation Relating Thereto: Its Ordinances and By-Laws, And Its Officers, 1877 -1888 (Box 1, Folder 3.5)
  - Ordinances and By-Laws of The Columbian University in The District of Columbia- Adopted at the Annual Meeting of the Corporation, 06/24/1873 (Box 1, Folder 3.6)
  - The George Washington University Ordinance for the Organization of the Educational Work- Approved by the Board of Trustees, 05/06/1909 (Box 1, Folder 3.7)
  - The George Washington University Code and Ordinances Governing the Academic Personnel of the University- Washington 6, D.C., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3.8)
  - Laws of the Columbian College in the District of Columbia, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3.9)
  - The Laws of The Columbian College in the District of Columbia as Approved by the Board of Trustees, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
  - Folder 4, undated (Box 1)
  - The George Washington University Regulations Governing Administrative Assistants and Research Personnel, 04/01/1954 (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
  - Folder 5, undated (Box 1)
  - Handbook of University-Wide Non-Academic Policies and Regulations Governing Student Conduct at the George Washington University- Academic Year 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5.1)
  - The Governance of The George Washington University Report of the Commission on Governance of the University May, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5.2)
  - Code and Ordinances Governing the Academic Personnel of The George Washington University Together with the Principles, Standards, and Procedures for the Implementation Thereof, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5.3)
  - The Board of Trustees and Officers of Administration, 1987 -1988 (Box 1, Folder 5.4)
  - Code and Ordinances Governing Librarians of the Staff of the University Library, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5.5)
  - The Charter and Acts Supplementary Thereto of the George Washington University, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5.6)
  - All-University Policies, Regulations, and Procedures of the George Washington University, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5.7)
  - Comments on the Subcommittee on University-Wide Regulations on the Draft Report on University-Wide Regulations, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5.8)
  - The Sunday Star article- "New GWU Faculty Code Hailed as Model Document", 06/21/1964 (Box 1, Folder 5.9)
  - University Charter, Amendments & Supplementary Acts. (Original Charter) Feb. 9, 1821 -- Section 7 Non-Sectarian Cause, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Elmer Louis Kayser, University Historian to Hon. Walter E. Fauntroy- (typed and handwritten copy), 11/13/1974 (Box 1, Folder 6.1)
  - Letter from Walter E. Fauntroy, Member of Congress to Dr. E. L. Kayser, University Historian, 10/29/1974 (Box 1, Folder 6.2)
  - An Act To amend the Act entitled "An Act to incorporate the American University", 02/24/1893 --06/24/1974 (Box 1, Folder 6.3)
  - The George Washington University Presents "Confidential-from Washington", 03/1947 (Box 1, Folder 6.4)
  - University Charter, Amendments, & Supplementary Acts (General), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Plan of the Columbian University, 04/25/1873 (Box 1, Folder 7.1)
  - Georgetown's Charter-Washington Post, 05/20/1961 (Box 1, Folder 7.2)
  - An Act concerning the college of Georgetown in the District of Columbia, 03/01/1815 (Box 1, Folder 7.3)
  - The George Washington University Presents "Confidential-from Washington", 03/1947 (Box 1, Folder 7.4)
  - Col. Coll. & the Baptist Church--Baptist Convention--Charter and By-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History of Congress (pp 151-152 2 copies, 857-858, 863-866, 864-865, 997-998), 01/1821 (Box 1, Folder 8.1)
  - History of Congress (pp 999-1000), 02/1821 (Box 1, Folder 8.2)
  - History of Congress (pp 27-28, 35-36, 39-42, 41-42, 99-100, 117-118, 123-124, 149-150), 12/1820 (Box 1, Folder 8.3)
  - History of Congress (pp 801-802), 01/1820 (Box 1, Folder 8.4)
  - Appendix: Public Acts of Congress (pp 1791-1796), 01/1821 --02/1821 (Box 1, Folder 8.5)
  - Baptist General Convention: Charter, undated (Box 1, Folder 8.6)
  - University Charter, Amendments, Supplementary Acts (Resolutions & Discussions Leading to Granting of Columbian College Charter), 1820 -1821 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Circular, 01/10/1827 (Box 1, Folder 9.1)
  - An Act to Incorporate the Columbian College in the District of Columbia, 02/09/1821 (Box 1, Folder 9.2)
  - Columbian College in the District of Columbia, 03/1825 (Box 1, Folder 9.3)
  - Columbian College: Report by the Committee on the District of Columbia, 03/12/1830 (Box 1, Folder 9.4)
  - University Charter, Amendments & Supplementary Acts (Act Sectarianizing the University), 03/18/1898 (Box 1, Folder 10)